we have a quarter Circle and some shapes
inside it our goal is to find the area
of the blue region the trick here is to
solve this problem without using
integration pause this video and try to
solve it on your own we start by drawing
a radius from the center of this quarter
Circle which goes through this point of
intersection which will divide
everything in half let's say that both
of these blue shapes are represented by
X the white shapes by Y and this one by
Z so now we know that the total blue
area is represented by 2 * x + 2 * Z we
need to figure out what x and z are
we're dealing with a quarter of a full
circle the area of a quarter circle is
given by the formula < * Radius 2 / 4
the radius here is four so we calculate
it as 4 * 4 so the area of the quarter
circle is 4 * pi this total area of the
quarter circle is equal to 2 * x + 2 * y
+ 2 * Z we also have a semicircle inside
this quarter Circle the area of a
semicircle is given by the pi * radius
squar / 2 the diameter is 4 so the
radius is 2 when we calculate it we get
2 * pi as the area of the red semicircle
this 2 pi is equal to 2 * x + y next
let's focus on a triangle inside this
semicircle which is obtained by dividing
this semicircle into half the height of
this semicircle will be the same as the
radius of this semicircle which is
two now the area of the triangle is
calculated as base time height divided
by two here both the base and height are
two so the triangle's area is is 2 now
it is clear that the x + triangle's area
equals the area of the quarter Circle so
we subtract this triangle from both
sides to get the value of x the area of
the quarter circle is pi * 2^ 2 / 4
which is pi and the triangle area is 2
so X is equal to < - 2 now we substitute
X in this equation to get the value of y
as four the blue area is equal to 2 * x
+ 2 * Z substituting y = 4 we get the
area of the blue region as 4 Pi - 8
square units so good